<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web Development on CineReal.info</title>
    <link>http://cinereal.info/categories/web-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web Development on CineReal.info</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 02:07:57 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://cinereal.info/categories/web-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Github Pages for your Website</title>
      <link>http://cinereal.info/article/github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 02:07:57 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cinereal.info/article/github-pages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When creating your website, blog or a simple portfolio page you&amp;rsquo;ll eventually come to the point where you need to find a service / place to upload it.
You can either choose a paid service or try one of the free options that are often not reliable, slow or include ads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or you try &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. You might have heard of Git or GitHub or even used it as version control system. Many companies use it in technical departments, wherever code is involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also works great to host any type of static websites (&lt;a href=&#34;http://cinereal.info/article/new-website-static-site-generator/&#34;&gt;More about static websites&lt;/a&gt;).
This entire website is hosted on GitHub, here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://cinereal.github.io/&#34;&gt;cinereal.github.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Github pages have the additional benefit of enforced SSL encryption (HTTPS).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article we go over setting up the simplest of websites to get familiar with the GitHub interface and learn how to use Git via command line to sync up your local repository to your GitHub page.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Website - Static Site Generators</title>
      <link>http://cinereal.info/article/new-website-static-site-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 11:14:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cinereal.info/article/new-website-static-site-generator/</guid>
      <description>The Challenge A few weeks ago I decided to finally upgrade my 10+ year old website. Initially I planned to use a content management system (CMS) but eventually had to realize that this wouldn&amp;rsquo;t work with my current web-server due to technical difficulties. The PHP memory limit is set so low on the provider side that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to install a CMS.
The Solution - Static Site Generators (SSG) In recent years static site generators have become more popular.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>