<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on CineReal.info</title>
    <link>https://cinereal.github.io/article/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on CineReal.info</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 02:07:57 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cinereal.github.io/article/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Github Pages for your Website</title>
      <link>https://cinereal.github.io/article/github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 02:07:57 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cinereal.github.io/article/github-pages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When creating your website, blog or a simple portfolio page you&amp;rsquo;ll eventually come to the point where you need to find a service / place to upload it.
You can either choose a paid service or try one of the free options that are often not reliable, slow or include ads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or you try &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. You might have heard of Git or GitHub or even used it as version control system. Many companies use it in technical departments, wherever code is involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also works great to host any type of static websites (&lt;a href=&#34;https://cinereal.github.io/article/new-website-static-site-generator/&#34;&gt;More about static websites&lt;/a&gt;).
This entire website is hosted on GitHub, here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://cinereal.github.io/&#34;&gt;cinereal.github.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Github pages have the additional benefit of enforced SSL encryption (HTTPS).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article we go over setting up the simplest of websites to get familiar with the GitHub interface and learn how to use Git via command line to sync up your local repository to your GitHub page.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lens Cast Calibration in Capture One</title>
      <link>https://cinereal.github.io/article/captureone-lens-cast-calibration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 04:12:23 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cinereal.github.io/article/captureone-lens-cast-calibration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-to-capture-one-part-2&#34;&gt;Introduction to Capture One [Part 2]&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-lens-menu&#34;&gt;The Lens Menu&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cinereal.github.io/images/captureone/lens.png&#34; alt=&#34;The Lens Menu&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;lens-cast-calibration-lcc&#34;&gt;Lens Cast Calibration (LCC)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lens Cast Calibration as to be done specifically for a shot setup hence it&amp;rsquo;s grayed out until a preset is created and applied. Each lens, camera, setting and lighting situation requires a unique calibration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cinereal.github.io/images/captureone/lcc.png&#34; alt=&#34;LCC Profile&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-lens-cast-calibration&#34;&gt;What is Lens Cast Calibration?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short we are trying to minimize the uneven white balance throughout the image introduced due to a various factors. In many cases we can ignore it since it&amp;rsquo;s not noticeable unless we have a side-by-side comparison. But there are cases where it&amp;rsquo;s important to have an even white balance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of these cases are snowy landscapes, which I&amp;rsquo;ve been shooting recently. This type of photography exposes issues in the white balance as illustrated in the photo below.
See how the color shifts towards the edges into a bluish darker tone?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cinereal.github.io/images/captureone/nolcc1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;LCC Off Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wide angle lenses are impacted the most as they gather light from more directions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lens Correction in Capture One</title>
      <link>https://cinereal.github.io/article/captureone-lens-correction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 01:20:13 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cinereal.github.io/article/captureone-lens-correction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-to-capture-one-part-1&#34;&gt;Introduction to Capture One [Part 1]&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-lens-menu&#34;&gt;The Lens Menu&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cinereal.github.io/images/captureone/lens.png&#34; alt=&#34;The Lens Menu&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;lens-correction&#34;&gt;Lens Correction&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on your lens and camera you might get either one of the following profiles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manufacturer Profile:&lt;/strong&gt; Manufacturers supply enough data in the RAW file to generate a profile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lens Specific Profile:&lt;/strong&gt; Means Capture One has a profile of your lens with additional Sharpness Falloff correction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cinereal.github.io/images/captureone/lenscorrection.png&#34; alt=&#34;Manufacturer Profile&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://cinereal.github.io/images/captureone/lenscorrectionprofile.png&#34; alt=&#34;Lens Specific Profile&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Raw Editor - Capture One</title>
      <link>https://cinereal.github.io/article/captureone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 12:22:57 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cinereal.github.io/article/captureone/</guid>
      <description>New Camera, New RAW Editor I recently upgraded my camera and thought this was a good opportunity to re-evaluate my choice of RAW editing software. In the past I tried a few open source options, RawTherapee and darktable. They are both pretty good but I was missing a few features that forced me to keep falling back on Photoshop plus Camera RAW and I never got used to the in my view slightly confusing interfaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Website - Static Site Generators</title>
      <link>https://cinereal.github.io/article/new-website-static-site-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 11:14:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cinereal.github.io/article/new-website-static-site-generator/</guid>
      <description>The Challenge A few weeks ago I decided to finally upgrade my 10+ year old website. Initially I planned to use a content management system (CMS) but eventually had to realize that this wouldn&amp;rsquo;t work with my current web-server due to technical difficulties. The PHP memory limit is set so low on the provider side that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to install a CMS.
The Solution - Static Site Generators (SSG) In recent years static site generators have become more popular.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>